Woman's Club of Albany; Records mss139
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications, 1911-2009; 7; 1.91 cubic ft.
  - The Messenger, 1960 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 8)
  - The Messenger, 1961 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 9)
  - The Messenger, 1962 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 10)
  - The Messenger, 1965 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 11)
  - The Messenger, ca. 1965 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 12)
  - The Messenger, 1966 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 13)
  - The Messenger, 1967 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 14)
  - The Messenger, 1968 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 15)
  - The Messenger, 1970 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 16)
  - The Messenger, 1971 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 17)
  - The Messenger, 1972 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 18)
  - The Messenger, 1973 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 19)
  - The Messenger, 1979 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 20)
  - The Messenger, ca. 1980 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Club and House Rental Information, ca. 1995 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Club Program, 1997-1998 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Club Program, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Club Informational Packet, 2007 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 25)
  - WCA Messenger, 2008-2009 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 26)
  - House Rental Informational Pamphlets (1 of 3), Undated (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 27)
  - House Rental Informational Pamphlets (2 of 3), Undated (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 28)
  - House Rental Informational Pamphlets (3 of 3), Undated (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 29)
- Subject Files, 1908-2018; 8; 3.93 cubic ft.
  The Subject Files series contains folders featuring a variety of topics, ranging from photographs of the Clubhouse and members to general correspondence to songs and poems. This series houses materials on the New York State Federation of Women's Clubs and the General Federation of Women's Clubs. It also contains newspaper clippings about the WCA and its members. Many clippings from the early twentieth century mention Mrs. Edward Cameron, who was very involved in the Albany community.
  There is an item in the general correspondence, pre-dating the establishment of the Woman's Club of Albany. A letter to Mrs. Blair about joining the Club is dated 1908, two years before the WCA was founded. It is unclear whether the date is correct.
  The "Exes" File consists of materials related to former Board members. The self-proclaimed "Exes" held an annual event on the anniversary of the WCA's founding.
  - General Correspondence, 1908-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Programs and Reports (1 of 3), 1912-1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Programs and Reports (2 of 3), 1912-1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Programs and Reports (3 of 3), 1912-1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1912-2007; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Civic and Social Interests, 1913; 1916-1917; 1924; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Program, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Clubhouse, 1914-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Guest Book, Woman's Club of albany, Inc., 1915-1929 (Oversized 8)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Reports and Programs, 1915-1916; 1922; 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History of the Club, 1915; 1919; 1940; 1970; 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Homemaking, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - World War I, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Period Advertisements Retained by the Club, 1917; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Correspondence and Supplemental Materials, 1917-1988; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings about the Woman's Club of Albany and its Members, 1917; 1925; 1951; 1969; 2007 (Flat-file 1)
  - Letters Pertaining to Stolen Checks, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - City of Albany, N.Y. Budget, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Books Retained by Parliamentary Law Committee (1 of 2), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Books Retained by Parliamentary Law Committee (2 of 2), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - City Problems, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Albany Mothers' Club, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The "Exes" File (1 of 2), 1922-1955; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The "Exes" File (2 of 2), 1922-1955; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Albany Public Library, Gifts for Children's Book-Shelves, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Frame Carved by Alice Pauline Schefer That Held Certificate of Incorporation, 1923 (Flat-file 2)
  - Grace Aguilar Literary Society, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Program, 1924 (Oversized 6)
  - New Books Added to the Albany Public Library, 1925-1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Publications on the American Home, 1928; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Songs and Poems Retained by the Club (1 of 2), 1933-1935; 1963-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Songs and Poems Retained by the Club (2 of 2), 1933-1935; 1963-1966; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - New York State Women's Joint Legislative Forum, 1935; 1948; 1960-1965; 1972; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mortgage Burning Occasion, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - United States Constitution Sesquicentennial Commission, 1938 (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographs from the Club, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Newsletters and Annual Reports, 1943-1944; 1968-1972; 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pictures of the Clubhouse, 1944; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Clubwoman and Clubwomen's Life magazines, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Supplemental Roster, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Unknown Member File from Annual Convention, 1950; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Directory, 1950; 1972; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Third District Meetings, 1951-1970; Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The History of the New York State Federation of Women's Clubs, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Troy Women's Club Yearbook and Booklet, 1952-1953; 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Pictures of Club Members, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Administration Program, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Awards Given to the Club, 1960; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Tri-County Meeting Reports, 1960; 1962; 1969; 1971; Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - New York State Committee for the Aging Report, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Historic Albany Foundation, 1968; 2006 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Philanthropic Works, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Pictures of Club Members, 1971-1972; 1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Agreement with Residents of the Clubhouse, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Communications with Caretakers/Residents, 1979; 2001-2003; Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Applications for Grants, 1994; 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Photo Negatives of the Clubhouse, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Projects, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - GFWC Annual Report, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Capital Projects, 2005; 2008 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Reports, 2005; 2010; Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Resources, 2006; Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Roof Restoration, 2006; Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Leadership, 2006-2008; 2012 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Archives, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Facilities Maintenance, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Archives, 2007-2010; 2015; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Email Communications, 2007-2010; 2015-2016 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Publicity, 2007-2010; Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Articles, 2008 (Oversized 2, Folder 6)
  - Pine Hills Elementary School Playground, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clubhouse Restoration, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Project Proposals, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Public Messaging, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Concept Design Study, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Support Letters, 2008-2010; Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Communications, 2009-2010; Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Archives, 2009-2010; 2016; 2019; Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Historical News, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook Notes, 2010; Undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Recognitions, 2010-2012; 2016; Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Acknowledgements, 2013; Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Communications, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Public Information, 2015; Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Community Support, 2016 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Related Organizational News, 2016; Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - August Activity, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Communications, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - July Activity, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - June Activity, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - March Activity, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - September Activity, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - End of Year, 2017 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Activities, 2017; Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - April Activity, 2017; Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - February Activity, 2017; Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - January Activity, 2017; Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - May Activity, 2017; Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - November Activity, 2017; Undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - October Activity, 2017; Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Leadership Communications, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Archives, Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Bridge Score Sheets and Playing Cards Featuring Local Businesses, Undated (Oversized 7)
  - Design, Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Glove Pattern Retained by the Club, Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Historical, Undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Historical Materials, Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Historical Planning, Undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Inventory of Items in Small Drawer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - News, Undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Photographs Presented to the Woman's Club of Albany by New York State Federation of Women's Clubs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Pictures of the First Three Presidents and the Clubhouse, Undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Postcard of the Albany Institute and Historical and Art Society, Undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Preservation and Restoration, Undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Rules and Regulations for Use of Rooms, Undated (Box 3, Folder 52)